<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>An Introduction to Data Science Methods in Education</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on An Introduction to Data Science Methods in Education</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignments</title>
      <link>/assignments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/assignments/</guid>
      <description>Homework (12-14) Weekly homework. To be submitted in the form of an R Markdown file (.Rmd) via Canvas. There are a few weeks in which we may not have homework for different reasons; why the number of homeworks is listed as 12-14.
 Individual final project Complete an individually-designed project that can take different forms (R Markdown Report, interactive Shiny app, interactive dashboard, etc.) related to identifying and solving a data-related problem in education using R (due approximately two-thirds of the way through the semester).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Exercise Week 2</title>
      <link>/exercises/exercise-week2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exercises/exercise-week2/</guid>
      <description>  Loading packages  loading data  looking at data  Basic dplyr operations Select
Filter
Arrange
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Class Exercise Week 2</title>
      <link>/exercises/exercise-week3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exercises/exercise-week3/</guid>
      <description>  Loading packages  loading data  looking at data  Basic dplyr operations Select
Filter
Arrange
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo Week 3</title>
      <link>/exercises/demo-week-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/exercises/demo-week-3/</guid>
      <description>  Reading in the Data  Rename the columns  Examining the columns  Mutating Columns  Stringr operations  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework 1</title>
      <link>/homework/hw1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/homework/hw1/</guid>
      <description>Loading, setting up Checking that the project is correct First, ensure that this .Rmd file is saved in the directory for the project that you created for the course.
 First, let’s install and load ggplot2 We’ll do so by running the following line of code. This line of code, though, is a bit different from most: it installs a new R “package” with specific, additional functionality. Installing R packages is very common.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homework and Readings</title>
      <link>/homework_readings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/homework_readings/</guid>
      <description>  Week 1 None
 Week 2 Homework:
Homework 1: https://github.com/alishinski/course-website/blob/master/content/homework/HW1.Rmd
Readings:
 Data Science in Education Using R (DSIEUR) chapter #3: https://datascienceineducation.com/c03.html   Week 3 Readings:
 R for Data Science Chapter #12 Tidy Data: https://r4ds.had.co.nz/tidy-data.html   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/presentations/</guid>
      <description>   Week 1: RMD, HTML, PDF
 Week 2: RMD, HTML, PDF
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schedule</title>
      <link>/schedule/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/schedule/</guid>
      <description>     Week Date Unit Topic Homework Assignment Exam    Week 1  Aug 19 1: Getting started Introductions to each other and to data science HW1    Week 2  Aug 24,26  Foundational skills: Projects, functions, packages, and data HW2    Week 3  Aug 31, Sep 2 2: Exploring data Wrangling and “tidying” data HW3    Week 4  Sep 7, 9  Summarizing data descriptively HW4    Week 5  Sep 14,16  Visualization data with the grammar of graphics HW5    Week 6  Sep 21, 23  More visualization with the grammar of graphics (and some data wrangling) HW6    Week 7  Sep 28, 30  Color, stacking and dodging bars, and faceting HW8    Week 8  Oct 5, 7  Summarizing data in tables HW9    Week 9  Oct 12, 14  More on tables and a gentle introduction to modeling HW10    Week 10 Oct 19, 21 3: Drawing conclusions Estimating parameters HW10 Final project proposal   Week 11 Oct 26, 28  Making inferences about effects HW11    Week 12 Nov 2, 4  Communicating results effectively HW12    Week 13 Nov 9, 11 4: Looking ahead A buffet of advanced methods (Part 1) HW13    Week 14 Nov 16, 18  A buffet of advanced methods (Part 2) HW14    Week 15 Nov 23  A buffet of advanced methods (Part 2) HW14    Week 16 Nov 30  A buffet of advanced methods (Part 2) HW14    Finals Week (Due by Dec 5)     Final project and presentation, Curating resources     </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>An Introduction to Data Science Methods in Education University of Tennessee, Knoxville
Course Section: TPTE 695 (PhD) and STEM 599
Meeting Time and Place: Thursday, 2:50 – 4:05 pm (online synchronous)
Course Credit Hours: 3
Zoom Meeting: https://tennessee.zoom.us/j/94135227830
Course Website: https://f21-intro-to-data-sci-methods-in-ed.netlify.app/
Faculty Contact Information Dr. Alex Lishinski (they/them)
alishins@utk.edu
Zoom: https://tennessee.zoom.us/j/2299533064
Website: https://www.alexlishinski.com
Please don’t hesitate to email or contact me on Slack with updates, questions or concerns. I will try to respond within 24 hours during the week and 48 hours on the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Videos</title>
      <link>/videos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/videos/</guid>
      <description>  Class recordings (password required; see Slack)  Week 2 Lecture   Homework videos  Topic videos  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
